<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Rishi Balakrishnan</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Rishi Balakrishnan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://githubuser.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>161 Review Page</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/161-review-page/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/161-review-page/</guid><description>Network Security
ARP
Wireless Local Networks: WPA2
DHCP
IP Routing
TCP / UDP
TLS
DNS
Web security
SQL Injection
Intro to the Web
Same-Origin Policy
CRSF
Cross-Site Scripting</description></item><item><title>Algorithms to Live By</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/algorithms-to-live-by/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/algorithms-to-live-by/</guid><description>Even where perfect algorithms haven’t been found, however, the battle between generations of computer scientists and the most intractable real-world problems has yielded a series of insights. These hard-won precepts are at odds with our intuitions about rationality, and they don’t sound anything like the narrow prescriptions of a mathematician trying to force the world into clean, formal lines. They say: Don’t always consider all your options. Don’t necessarily go for the outcome that seems best every time.</description></item><item><title>ARP</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/arp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/arp/</guid><description>Address Resolution Protocol - Purpose is to translate IP addresses into MAC addresses
Layer 2 of the internet stack
Original Ethernet was designed to broadcast all messages to machines in local network (machine should just ignore messages that are not meant for it)
ARP Protocol:
Broadcast: Send IP address and ask for MAC Response: Send MAC address that corresponds to IP - if IP is outside of LAN the router should respond with its MAC address Cache: Cache mapping Attack</description></item><item><title>articles</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/articles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/articles/</guid><description>Readwise</description></item><item><title>As the Pirates Become CEOs - The Closing of the Open Internet</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/as-the-pirates-become-ceos-the-closing-of-the-open-internet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/as-the-pirates-become-ceos-the-closing-of-the-open-internet/</guid><description>In 2015, Hossein Derakhshan–who has been called the “grandfather” of the Iranian blogosphere–left prison after serving six years of a nineteen-year sentence for blogging, including long stretches of solitary confinement. But prison did not break him; instead, he says, what nearly broke his heart was what he found online when he started blogging again.8
After being released, Derakhshan learned that he needed to adapt to the new digital environment and use the new commercial social networks.</description></item><item><title>Billionaires Are a Security Threat</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/billionaires-are-a-security-threat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/billionaires-are-a-security-threat/</guid><description>The overly conservative approach to intellectual property that makes things proprietary in the first place is also a liability that compromises everything a company might create because it empowers billionaires to kill them. (View Highlight)
Blockchains fight this problem on the deepest level possible. It would be vastly more difficult, or perhaps impossible, for Musk to kill off a blockchain so long as a handful of users objected enough to continue operating independent nodes.</description></item><item><title>Blockchain and Democracy</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/blockchain-and-democracy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/blockchain-and-democracy/</guid><description>11/17 - I’ve been thinking about this specifically yesterday and generally over the past couple weeks. Yesterday I was reading this article and listening to this podcast by Eli Zegler
The podcast and the article discussed Quadratic Voting / Funding and their uses to strengthen democracy, specifically in the context of participatory budgeting. Quadratic Funding allows people to express the strength of their preferences while also ensuring that things that people care about (that aren’t the most important thing) still get funded.</description></item><item><title>books</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/books/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/books/</guid><description>Readwise</description></item><item><title>Brooklyn Micro-grid</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/brooklyn-micro-grid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/brooklyn-micro-grid/</guid><description>Homepage here</description></item><item><title>Bullshit Jobs - David Graeber</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/bullshit-jobs-david-graeber/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/bullshit-jobs-david-graeber/</guid><description>We have become a civilization based on work—not even “productive work” but work as an end and meaning in itself. We have come to believe that men and women who do not work harder than they wish at jobs they do not particularly enjoy are bad people unworthy of love, care, or assistance from their communities. It is as if we have collectively acquiesced to our own enslavement. (Location 256)</description></item><item><title>Calendar</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/calendar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/calendar/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Callings</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/callings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/callings/</guid><description>Being given this dopamine firehose at such a young age has shaped my brain’s choice calculus in difficult-to-define ways. My mind’s decision-making process doesn’t default to what I’d find most satisfying — it instead filters for which options would be both respected and easily understood by my audience.</description></item><item><title>Can Mesh Networks and Offline Wireless Move From Protest Tools to News?</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/can-mesh-networks-and-offline-wireless-move-from-protest-tools-to-news/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/can-mesh-networks-and-offline-wireless-move-from-protest-tools-to-news/</guid><description>During Occupy Wall Street, for example, an Internet-based discussion forum “forum was good, but a lot of it was from people who were not in New York City,” says Dan Phiffer, an artist and technologist at The New Yorker. “I didn’t feel like it was serving the people who were actually in the space that well.” (View Highlight)
At Occupy Wall Street, Phiffer deployed a chat forum and content repository run off a small wifi router and USB stick he dubbed occupy.</description></item><item><title>Carbon Democracy</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/carbon-democracy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/carbon-democracy/</guid><description>Democracy is based on a model, an original idea, that can be copied from one place to the next. &amp;hellip; Once one has made democracy into something that moves around the world as an idea, in order to move with it, one is committed to a particular way of explaining how the idea works, how people become democratic. If democracy is an idea, then countries become democratic by the idea getting into people’s heads.</description></item><item><title>Changing the ‘World as It Is’ Into the ‘World as It Should Be’</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/changing-the-world-as-it-is-into-the-world-as-it-should-be/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/changing-the-world-as-it-is-into-the-world-as-it-should-be/</guid><description>Radical movements seeking to alter the material conditions of people’s daily lives must first contend with the constraints created by those conditions — including the despondency engendered by a system more accountable to moneyed interests than ordinary people. They must deal with the reality of power as a guiding force in the world.
Critics of Alinsky’s model of community organizing see focusing on “the world as it is” as a way of avoiding ideology and hemming in a movement’s more radical aspirations.</description></item><item><title>CJDNS Whitepaper.md</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/cjdns-whitepaper.md/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/cjdns-whitepaper.md/</guid><description>Each of these problems is a tragedy of the commons problem. The users of virus infected computers are incentivized to save money rather than purchasing a product or service to rid their computer of the infection. While there are solutions such as egress filtering which decrease the problem, ISPs are incentivized to implement as little security as possible because they are not directly affected. Denial of service, whether by packet flooding or by faux legal action, benefits the attacker who is able to hide the truth or victimize service providers as well as organizations who make it their business to provide DoS related services.</description></item><item><title>Collaboration at Scale - Blockchain and Mutual Aid</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/collaboration-at-scale-blockchain-and-mutual-aid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/collaboration-at-scale-blockchain-and-mutual-aid/</guid><description>Many supporters of mutual aid advocate that most charity and nonprofit models not only fail to solve systemic issues, but actually work to perpetuate the inequality that these systems create. By holding all of the donation dollars, charity board members alone get to decide who is worthy of support and who is not. Their processes for this decision making often follow existing societal biases (e.g. only providing support to people who are “sober” or employed) and are influenced by elite donors.</description></item><item><title>Columbia higher education strike</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/columbia-higher-education-strike/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/columbia-higher-education-strike/</guid><description>This article makes it seem that pay raises weren&amp;rsquo;t one of the biggest issues: union recognition and neutral arbitration were the two biggest</description></item><item><title>Community Digital Gardens</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/community-digital-gardens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/community-digital-gardens/</guid><description>Related to Digital Gardens
TODO: Look into federated wikis
Reasoning
Idea
V1
Have feed of changes made to digital garden with feed offering chances to comment on changes, which could also be integrated into the digital garden itself
Offer some functionality in the reverse direction as well, with discussions or posts (either manually or automatically tagged as related to some content) having some way to be integrated into the digital garden as well</description></item><item><title>Community Micro-Grid Projects</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/community-micro-grid-projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/community-micro-grid-projects/</guid><description>Brooklyn Micro-grid</description></item><item><title>Cool NYC Projects</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/cool-nyc-projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/cool-nyc-projects/</guid><description>PactDAO
Brooklyn Micro-grid
NYC Mesh</description></item><item><title>Cross-Site Scripting</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/cross-site-scripting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/cross-site-scripting/</guid><description>aka XSS
Basically the insertion of Javascript into some webpage such that when the webpage is loaded the javascript is as well with the origin of the webpage which means that Same-Origin Policy can be thwarted
Can either be stored in the webpage or stored within the parameters of a request that the user is tricked into making
Defense:
Sanitize - this can be tricky but there is apparently a set of robust sanitization practices Content Security Policy - scripts can only be loaded in from a list of approved domains per web server</description></item><item><title>CRSF</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/crsf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/crsf/</guid><description>Related to implementation of [Cookies](Cookies: Key-value pairs ) and session tokens
Basically attacker tricks user&amp;rsquo;s browser into making a GET/POST request with malicious parameters to a website which the user is logged into - the browser will automatically send the session token along with the request which makes the action succeed Defense
CSRF Token - server generates token associated with every form, which is checked on form submission
Server needs to maintain mapping of session tokens to CSRF Referer Validation</description></item><item><title>DAO</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/dao/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/dao/</guid><description/></item><item><title>DHCP</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/dhcp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/dhcp/</guid><description>Connecting to network requires IP address, IP address of DNS server, IP address of router
DHCP Handshake:
Client Discover: Broadcast Request for config Server offer: Server responds with potential configuration. This often comes with a lease after which the client must rebroadcast request for configuration or server frees settings (like IP) for use by another client Client request: Client broadcasts which config it&amp;rsquo;s chosen Server Acknowledge: Server confirms that its config has been chosen Network Address Translation: More devices than IP addresses and not all networks support IPv6 (which allows for more IP addresses) -&amp;gt; Multiple devices in same network can share IP addresses.</description></item><item><title>Differential Privacy</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/differential-privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/differential-privacy/</guid><description>[[Fundamental Law of Information Recovery]] states that overly accurate answers to too many questions will destroy privacy regardless of privacy protecting method - DP just tries to postpone this
DP protects against attacks that use auxiliary information
Differential Privacy/Basic Terms</description></item><item><title>Differential Privacy/Basic Terms</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/differential-privacy/basic-terms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/differential-privacy/basic-terms/</guid><description>Interactive: Queries run adaptively based on responses vs Non-interactive: Sanitized data / summary statistics released</description></item><item><title>Digital Gardens</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/digital-gardens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/digital-gardens/</guid><description>The stream and the garden - analogy from this article
The stream
How most of social media operates right now. Content is ordered chronologically/algorithmically and as a result dissolves quickly. You don’t really get a chance to pause the flow of content and revisit ideas, and it’s hard to see the connections between ideas as well.
How form affects content:
Structure of the stream incentivizes content to be as attention-grabbing as possible because it&amp;rsquo;s ephemeral.</description></item><item><title>DNS</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/dns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/dns/</guid><description>Translates human readable URL into IP address
Name servers create a hierarchy which help find specific IP addresses. For finding IP address of eecs.berkeley.edu first ask .edu name server, which routes you to .berkeley.edu name server, which then routes to eecs.berkeley.edu name server
Each response includes name / IP address of next name server down the hierarchy ISP usually provides DNS Recursive Resolver which sends these queries and then processes/caches results.</description></item><item><title>Economies of Virtue - The Circulation of 'Ethics' in AI</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/economies-of-virtue-the-circulation-of-ethics-in-ai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/economies-of-virtue-the-circulation-of-ethics-in-ai/</guid><description>That is, in order to circulate freely between the academy and industry, the ethical content (in terms of effects on the world—or at least the business to which they are directed) must be effaced or at least constrained. As the abhorrent treatment of prominent AI ethics researcher Timnit Gebru by her former employer Google demonstrates,47 when the ethics commodity fundamentally challenges business models, the appointments and status offered in exchange disappear (and worse).</description></item><item><title>Elite Capture</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/elite-capture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/elite-capture/</guid><description>One could not expect Black women to be wholly active in political movements that neither represented nor advanced their interests”; therefore, the identity politics they developed served as “entry points for Black women to engage in politics,” rather than a whole cloth withdrawal from problematic organizations and movements.
The collective’s principled stance on identity politics functioned as a principle of unity, rather than division
they were in favor of diverse coalitional organizing</description></item><item><title>Entangled Life - How Fungi Make Our Worlds, Change Our Minds &amp; Shape Our Futures</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/entangled-life-how-fungi-make-our-worlds-change-our-minds-shape-our-futures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/entangled-life-how-fungi-make-our-worlds-change-our-minds-shape-our-futures/</guid><description>Many of the most dramatic events on Earth have been—and continue to be—a result of fungal activity. Plants only made it out of the water around five hundred million years ago because of their collaboration with fungi, which served as their root systems for tens of million years until plants could evolve their own. Today, more than ninety percent of plants depend on mycorrhizal fungi—from the Greek words for fungus (mykes) and root (rhiza)—which can link trees in shared networks sometimes referred to as the “wood wide web.</description></item><item><title>full-title</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/full-title/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/full-title/</guid><description>[]</description></item><item><title>Games_Agency_as_Art</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/games_agency_as_art/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/games_agency_as_art/</guid><description>Games ends are extremely different from the sorts of ends we stand behind in ordinary life. Our values, in ordinary life, are largely recalci- trant. Much of what we value seems universal and immoveable. We value life, freedom, and happiness. &amp;hellip; We can &amp;hellip; change our in-​game ends easily and fluidly. We can adopt new ends, which will guide our actions for the duration of the game, and then drop them in an instant.</description></item><item><title>Governing the Commons - Elinor Ostrom</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/governing-the-commons-elinor-ostrom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/governing-the-commons-elinor-ostrom/</guid><description>The tragedy of the commons, the prisoner’s dilemma, and the logic of collective action are closely related concepts in the models that have defined the accepted way of viewing many problems that individuals face when attempting to achieve collective benefits. At the heart of each of these models is the free-rider problem. Whenever one person cannot be excluded from the benefits that others provide, each person is motivated not to contribute to the joint effort, but to free-ride on the efforts of others.</description></item><item><title>Hidden Cafe</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/hidden-cafe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/hidden-cafe/</guid><description>01/25/2023
I went today and I really enjoyed myself. I was sitting right next to some people that were deeply involved with indigenous justice efforts and it was definitely a new type of conversation to overhear. There were tons of dogs and children running around, and the cafe itself was pretty small with the a book shelf lining the back wall. I met a guy named Ian who carried around a &amp;ldquo;Personal Ads Book&amp;rdquo; in which people could jot down a blurb about themselves and their contact information in the hopes that somebody later (who&amp;rsquo;s also about to create an ad) would read about it and contact them.</description></item><item><title>higher ed strike strategy</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/higher-ed-strike-strategy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/higher-ed-strike-strategy/</guid><description>Columbia higher education strike</description></item><item><title>Hunter Gatherer Societies</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/hunter-gatherer-societies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/hunter-gatherer-societies/</guid><description>Radically egalitarian
Based on this video
They lived in harmony in nature and any sense of pride (that came from things like over-hunting) was threatening to both the tribe and nature so males that exhibited these signs were humbled by the tribe
Had system of demand sharing where anybody that wanted something from someone else could just take it and it was considered very rude to refused - ensured no one person every accumulated too much and is very antithetical to the notion of private property.</description></item><item><title>Hyperconnected Culture and Its Discontents</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/hyperconnected-culture-and-its-discontents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/hyperconnected-culture-and-its-discontents/</guid><description>Digital abundance is a mixed blessing: exhilarating, yet flattening and homogenizing. Culture is converted into “content” that blurs together as it flows through the same conduits and across the same interfaces in an endless stream. As we struggle to keep abreast of the accelerating flow of content, drawn by the perpetual lure of the new, we come to know less and less about more and more. (View Highlight) The digital media scholar Jean Burgess has identified a key tension in technology design between “usability” and “hackability,” the former emphasizing “easy access to a predetermined set of simple operations” and the latter open-ended manipulability and scope for “complex experimentation.</description></item><item><title>I Didn’t Want It to Be True, but the Medium Really Is the Message</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/i-didnt-want-it-to-be-true-but-the-medium-really-is-the-message/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/i-didnt-want-it-to-be-true-but-the-medium-really-is-the-message/</guid><description>Our conventional response to all media, namely that it is how they are used that counts, is the numb stance of the technological idiot. For the ‘content’ of a medium is like the juicy piece of meat carried by the burglar to distract the watchdog of the mind.”
In his prophetic 1985 book, “Amusing Ourselves to Death,” Postman argued that the dystopia we must fear is not the totalitarianism of George Orwell’s “1984” but the narcotized somnolence of Aldous Huxley’s “Brave New World.</description></item><item><title>I Was Lost Until I Became a Stoic</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/i-was-lost-until-i-became-a-stoic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/i-was-lost-until-i-became-a-stoic/</guid><description>Viktor Frankl—whose Holocaust memoir Man’s Search for Meaning should be on every human’s reading list—put it most succinctly: “Everything can be taken from a man but one thing: the last of the human freedoms—to choose one&amp;rsquo;s attitude in any given set of circumstances.” You could be doing something so banal as sitting in traffic, or getting stuck in a boring dinner conversation. Amor fati, a Stoic would say. Love your fate.</description></item><item><title>I Write the Songs</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/i-write-the-songs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/i-write-the-songs/</guid><description>The beauty is its algorithm is so efficient that its interest graph [TikTok’s database of which users are interested in what] can be assembled without imposing much of a burden on the user at all. It is passive personalization, learning through consumption. Because the videos are so short, the volume of training data a user provides per unit of time is high. Because the videos are entertaining, this training process feels effortless, even enjoyable, for the user.</description></item><item><title>Intro to the Web</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/intro-to-the-web/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/intro-to-the-web/</guid><description>URL&amp;rsquo;s (e.g. http://calcentral.berkeley.edu/academics) have three parts
Protocol: &amp;ldquo;http&amp;rdquo; Location: &amp;ldquo;calcentral.berkeley.edu&amp;rdquo; - this can also include a username or port number Path: &amp;ldquo;academics&amp;rdquo; - what resource to request from the server. Can supply key-value arguments after &amp;ldquo;?&amp;rdquo; character, like &amp;ldquo;?key1=value1&amp;amp;key2=value2&amp;rdquo; and possible anchor which is interpreted by the browser that tells it where in the webpage to go HTTP: Operates as series of requests and responses
Request types: GET and POST</description></item><item><title>IP Routing</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/ip-routing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/ip-routing/</guid><description>IP address used to uniquely identify devices on whole internet (abstracting away [NAT](Network Address Translation: More devices than IP addresses and not all networks support IPv6 (which allows for more IP addresses) -&amp;gt; Multiple devices in same network can share IP addresses. ) )
IPv4 consists of 32 bytes with specified prefix size (e.g. 161.22/16 has prefix size 16) where prefix specifies a subnet and max number of devices on subnet is 2^(32 - prefix size)</description></item><item><title>Kim Stanley Robinson - The Ministry for the Future_ a Novel</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/kim-stanley-robinson-the-ministry-for-the-future_-a-novel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/kim-stanley-robinson-the-ministry-for-the-future_-a-novel/</guid><description>Consider the Greek goddess of justice. Bronze woman in a toga, with a blindfold covering her eyes to make her be fair. Her scales held up to measure the balance of crime and punishment, no consideration given to individual influence. But nothing ever really balances in those scales. If it’s an eye for an eye, maybe. That will balance out. But if someone is killed, no. The murderer gets fined, or jailed for life— is that a real balance?</description></item><item><title>Less Is More</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/less-is-more/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/less-is-more/</guid><description>Recent figures show that around 85% of global fish stocks are now depleted or facing collapse. &amp;hellip; corporations have turned fishing into an act of warfare, using industrial megatrawlers to scrape the seafloor in their hunt for increasingly scarce fish, hauling up hundreds of species in order to catch the few that have ‘market value’, turning coral gardens and colourful (Location 180)
This is the thing about ecology: everything is interconnected.</description></item><item><title>Local Farming</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/local-farming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/local-farming/</guid><description>Local farming initiatives
Cut down on large corporate supply chains that emit a lot of carbon
Cycle returns back into the community and give the community more control</description></item><item><title>Long Live Participatory Socialism!</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/long-live-participatory-socialism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/long-live-participatory-socialism/</guid><description>one cannot just be “against” capitalism or neoliberalism; one must above all be “for” something else, which requires precisely designating the ideal economic system that one wishes to set up, the just society that one has in mind, whatever name one finally decides to give it.
the share of the poorest 50% has never stopped being tiny. The situation of the poorest 50% has improved more in terms of income than in terms of wealth (their share of total income has grown from ba</description></item><item><title>Many Wisdoms</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/many-wisdoms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/many-wisdoms/</guid><description>While the quest for a common humanity is certainly present in ancient texts, there is also an idea in wisdom traditions that, to truly be wise, we have to learn to live with different ideas of the truth. Wisdom in this sense is not separate from identity, but is about figuring out how humans can live well and develop universal standards of wellbeing, while also knowing that no single standard of wellness will ever be meaningful to everyone (View Highlight)</description></item><item><title>Mesh Networks</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/mesh-networks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/mesh-networks/</guid><description>Mesh Networks Primer
Reasons to support
More community control over the Internet. This means decreasing the power of ISP&amp;rsquo;s and extending coverage to places where it usually wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be good, if at all present like NYC Mesh id:: 63a29d6b-0f9c-4443-a9ab-11cfce06c9d0
More resilient to natural disasters because there&amp;rsquo;s no central point of failure id:: 63a29d68-d5e4-49e9-8006-a31dff772ba2 More censorship-resistant because the community has control over which web traffic is allowed, which is powerful during a protest.</description></item><item><title>Mesh Networks Primer</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/mesh-networks-primer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/mesh-networks-primer/</guid><description>Ideal properties
Self-forming/organizing: Easy to incorporate new nodes into network
Self-healing: Gracefully handle node failures.
Self-optimization: Arrange to maximize coverage</description></item><item><title>Night Storm</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/night-storm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/night-storm/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Death ends a life, not a relationship.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>No Bosses - What It’s Like Working at a DAO</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/archive.ph/IMQyx</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/archive.ph/IMQyx</guid><description>To start from the top, dOrg has no general management positions (CEO, CFO, etc). &amp;hellip; Instead, roles are fluid, with people sliding into different roles depending on each project. Everyone who officially works at the company is a legal owner of its Vermont LLC, with each owner owning one share. Company decisions are voted on using tokens, which accrue as you complete projects for the company. &amp;hellip; The company isn’t completely non-hierarchical, however.</description></item><item><title>No Hard Reset - Against the Crypto Utopia</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/no-hard-reset-against-the-crypto-utopia-zora-zine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/no-hard-reset-against-the-crypto-utopia-zora-zine/</guid><description>Like other technologies, blockchain urbanism cannot replace the fundamentals of urban development, which is to say a human-centered approach. Without the social integration of this technology across all sectors, it’s not a city: it’s just a solution in search of a problem.
the fabled crypto utopia and successful case studies of mixed-reality cities are caught in the same bind: their architecture assumes a lack of trust amongst citizens and governments, with either the full transparency of public chains or the tougher security of private chains pitching to solve the perma-problem of trustlessness.</description></item><item><title>NYC Mesh</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/nyc-mesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/nyc-mesh/</guid><description>Homepage here</description></item><item><title>Orwell's Roses</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/orwells-roses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/orwells-roses/</guid><description>There’s an Etruscan word, saeculum, that describes the span of time lived by the oldest person present, sometimes calculated to be about a hundred years. In a looser sense, the word means the expanse of time during which something is in living memory. &amp;hellip; trees seemed to offer another kind of saeculum, a longer time scale and deeper continuity, giving shelter from our ephemerality the way that a tree might offer literal shelter under its boughs.</description></item><item><title>Our Contaminated Future</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/our-contaminated-future/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/our-contaminated-future/</guid><description>In Fukushima, I found a society collapsing under the weight of industrial pollution. But that’s only part of the story. I also found toxic solidarity. Rather than giving up, Tanizaki and other farmers have taken matters into their own hands, embracing novel practices for living alongside toxic pollution. These practices go far beyond traditional ‘farming’. They involve weaving relationships with scientists, starting independent decontamination experiments, piloting projects to create food security, and developing new ways to monitor a changing environment.</description></item><item><title>Our Way Out - Dual Power and the Future of Organizing</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/our-way-out-dual-power-and-the-future-of-organizing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/our-way-out-dual-power-and-the-future-of-organizing/</guid><description>Dual power is a two-part strategy that consists of public resistance to oppression (counter-power) and the building of alternative democratic, participatory institutions (counter-institutions). In other words, one part fights the existing systems by mobilizing against them while the other builds resilient, people-led institutions to take their plac (View Highlight)
Building digital dual power means building digital democracy - platforms, protocols and toolkits that can be co-designed and co-governed to serve collective needs over individual capital gain.</description></item><item><title>Platform Socialism</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/platform-socialism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/platform-socialism/</guid><description>Separating questions of ownership and governance is an important step because it enables smaller communities to exercise control over services that may require large amounts of capital investment in digital infrastructure
For a privileged few, almost anything can be streamed or delivered straight to your home. For the rest, their job is to label data, assemble products and deliver packages, all to ensure that no cracks appear in the smooth functioning of our automated future.</description></item><item><title>public</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/public/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/public/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Railworkers Feel Like They Have Very Little Left to Lose at This Point</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/ryan-grim-railworkers-feel-like-they-have-very-little-left-to-lose-at-this-point/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/ryan-grim-railworkers-feel-like-they-have-very-little-left-to-lose-at-this-point/</guid><description>The ’26 act also included a union shop clause, which gave legal recognition to the unions. This meant that, in some ways, the unions had less incentive to keep organizing their workers because they were legally locked in and because they knew Congress was going to step in and strike a deal. Nobody had any incentive to do anything more than just go through the motions. (View Highlight)
AOC and the Squad got roasted for voting to impose the contract.</description></item><item><title>Reading List</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/reading-list/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/reading-list/</guid><description>Currently Reading
Games: Agency as Art by C Thi Nguyen
Bullshit Jobs - David Graeber: Have heard a lot about this book in particular
To Read
Nonfiction
Governing the Commons - Elinor Ostrom: I think that this book will be more academic but especially after reading Less is More I want to read more about the Commons and what it takes to sustain them
The User Illusion: Cutting Consciousness Down to Size</description></item><item><title>Readwise</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/readwise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/readwise/</guid><description>On [[Nov 30th, 2022]] at 9:32 AM Readwise synced 2 highlights from 1 book.
On [[Dec 2nd, 2022]] at 1:37 AM Readwise synced 137 highlights from 15 books.
On [[Dec 5th, 2022]] at 12:23 AM Readwise synced 1 highlight from 1 book.
On [[Dec 7th, 2022]] at 12:04 AM Readwise synced 151 highlights from 17 books.
On [[Dec 9th, 2022]] at 7:55 PM Readwise synced 68 highlights from 2 books.</description></item><item><title>Researchers Say Time Is an Illusion. So Why Are We All Obsessed With It?</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/researchers-say-time-is-an-illusion.-so-why-are-we-all-obsessed-with-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/researchers-say-time-is-an-illusion.-so-why-are-we-all-obsessed-with-it/</guid><description>Those light cycles are the &amp;ldquo;tick&amp;rdquo; of the clock. By averaging a subset of the 21 clocks together, NIST has created a system that can count the time to within one quadrillionth of a second. That means the government&amp;rsquo;s clock can keep time to within a second over the course of about 30 million years. In another room, that timing signal is sent out across the United States, and via satellite to other government laboratories in other parts of the world with clocks of their own.</description></item><item><title>Ron DeSantis Is Siding With Powerful Insurance Companies Against Florida Policyholders</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/ron-desantis-is-siding-with-powerful-insurance-companies-against-florida-policyholders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/ron-desantis-is-siding-with-powerful-insurance-companies-against-florida-policyholders/</guid><description>Florida’s one-way attorney fee law allows a policyholder who successfully sues an insurance company that refused to pay a claim to make that insurance company pay their legal bills, too.
This law is essentially a slingshot that David can use to fight Goliath. It’s meant to discourage insurance companies from dragging their feet when a policyholder files a claim — and to ensure those policyholders aren’t punished if they must sue to collect.</description></item><item><title>Same-Origin Policy</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/same-origin-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/same-origin-policy/</guid><description>Different tabs in browser not allowed to communicate with each other unless they have the &amp;ldquo;same origin&amp;rdquo;
Origin is determined by creating a (protocol, domain name, port) tuple and if tuple is the same then two websites have the same origin EXCEPT
JavaScript runs with origin of page that loaded it Images have origin of page that it comes from Frames have origin of URL where frame is from</description></item><item><title>Social Media for Organizing</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/social-media-for-organizing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/social-media-for-organizing/</guid><description>Current social media (with design motives being profit driven) seems inadequate for organizers who want to facilitate movement growth
Leftist culture seems very prone to call-outs that focus on people rather than ideas One potential idea is Community Digital Gardens</description></item><item><title>Solarpunk</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/solarpunk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/solarpunk/</guid><description>Optimistic movement that reimagines technology as co-constructive with nature rather than oppositional. Focuses on giving power back to local autonomous units and ensuring self-sufficiency. Anti-capitalist.
Local self-sufficiency includes:
Local power generating like Community Micro-Grid Projects
Local internet control with Mesh Networks
Food system based on Local Farming
Such a cool aesthetic</description></item><item><title>SQL Injection</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/sql-injection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/sql-injection/</guid><description>Process of manipulating inputs to SQL queries to create unintended behavior
Usually pass in some mix of garbage input to make sure that the intended query doesn&amp;rsquo;t return anything, as well as other input that has &amp;rsquo; or &amp;quot; and ; to start a &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; SQL query within the bounds of the old one Defense
Escaping characters in SQL - issue is that characters can just be escaped twice and then we&amp;rsquo;re back to where we started Parametrized SQL - prepare statements with areas to plug in parameters.</description></item><item><title>Swerving Censors With Absurdity - Why Is China’s Underground Music Scene So Weird?</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/swerving-censors-with-absurdity-why-is-chinas-underground-music-scene-so-weird/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/swerving-censors-with-absurdity-why-is-chinas-underground-music-scene-so-weird/</guid><description>Absurdity is hard for a government to crack down on. You might be able to ban phrases, words, topics and ideologies, but how do you ban something about a redheaded man who didn’t have a head? To put that in official print would highlight the inherent oppressive ridiculousness of the government system itself. Thus, weirdness becomes a liberal vanguard.</description></item><item><title>TCP / UDP</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/tcp-/-udp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/tcp-/-udp/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Agenda Podcast Explores How DAOs Can Strengthen Workers’ Rights</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-agenda-podcast-explores-how-daos-can-strengthen-workers-rights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-agenda-podcast-explores-how-daos-can-strengthen-workers-rights/</guid><description>a union forms because there’s a misalignment between the business and its employees. Hopefully, a DAO won’t have that kind of misalignment.” (View Highlight)</description></item><item><title>The Alignment Problem</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-alignment-problem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-alignment-problem/</guid><description>Dwork, then at Microsoft Research, came up to Berkeley to meet with fellow computer scientist Amos Fiat. They spent the entire day talking. By lunchtime, as they sat down together in beloved local restaurant Chez Panisse
One engineer I spoke with complained that his management repeatedly stressed the importance of making sure that models aren’t skewed by sensitive attributes like gender and race—but his company’s privacy policy prevents him and the other machine-learning engineers from accessing the protected attributes of the records they’re working with.</description></item><item><title>The Atlas of AI</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-atlas-of-ai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-atlas-of-ai/</guid><description>In the case of AI, there is no singular black box to open, no secret to expose, but a multitude of interlaced systems of power. Complete transparency, then, is an impossible goal
Strubell’s team found that running only a single NLP model produced more than 660,000 pounds of carbon dioxide emissions, the equivalent of five gas-powered cars over their total lifetime (including their manufacturing) or 125 round-trip flights from New York to Beijing.</description></item><item><title>The Commons</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-commons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-commons/</guid><description>Communal resource that&amp;rsquo;s antithetical to the notion of private property
While capitalism maintains (and needs) artificial scarcity, the commons are based on abundance and equitable access. Maintaining the commons is probably the best way to create a [society of abundance](Capitalism transforms even the most spectacular gains in productivity and income not into abundance and human freedom, but into new forms of artificial scarcity. It must, or else it risks shutting down the engine of accumulation itself.</description></item><item><title>The Cybernetic Sex Worker</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-cybernetic-sex-worker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-cybernetic-sex-worker/</guid><description>Missing from this historical narrative of the internet, however, is the role sex workers have played in its development. The sex worker has always been a major stakeholder in telecommunications. As Melissa Gira Grant notes in Playing the Whore, ‘Prostitution is a communications technology. It signals.’ The term ‘call girl’ most explicitly exemplifies this, coined when city brothels were some of the first establishments to install telephone lines. (View Highlight)</description></item><item><title>The Happiness Hypothesis</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-happiness-hypothesis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-happiness-hypothesis/</guid><description>Freud, Plato, and Buddha all lived in worlds full of domesticated animals. They were familiar with the struggle to assert one’s will over a creature much larger than the self. But as the twentieth century wore on, cars replaced horses, and technology gave people ever more control over their physical worlds. When people looked for metaphors, they saw the mind as the driver of a car, or as a program running on a computer.</description></item><item><title>The Making of the Tech Worker Movement</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-making-of-the-tech-worker-movement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-making-of-the-tech-worker-movement/</guid><description>Software engineers, product designers, and others enjoyed better conditions than most workers, but they were still workers. Their privileged position gave them a degree of autonomy in their workplaces and, in some cases, non-negligible equity stakes in their firms—these were the bourgeois elements in their contradictory class position. A select few would even ascend into upper management or acquire enough capital to become truly bourgeois. But most would remain in the middle layers, and among the proletarian aspects of this location was the exclusion from real decision-making—namely, investment and production decisions such as whether to build a piece of software for the Trump Administration.</description></item><item><title>The Meaning of Anti-Work</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-meaning-of-anti-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-meaning-of-anti-work/</guid><description>The money we get from work sustains us just enough to keep us coming back to work.Our time away from work is spent travelling to or from work, or getting ready for work.Leisure itself is just nonwork for the sake of work.It’s the limited time we spend recovering from work and trying to distract ourselvesfrom work.Because of work, we’re constantly under the tyranny of the clock.It’s like what Bob Black claims Socrates once said : Manual labourers make bad friends and bad citizens because they have no time to fulfil the responsibilities of friendship and citizenship.</description></item><item><title>The Oceanic Fallout of Deep-Sea Mining</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-oceanic-fallout-of-deep-sea-mining/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-oceanic-fallout-of-deep-sea-mining/</guid><description>Scientists suspect that the footprint of nodule mining—currently the most popular form of seabed mining—will extend well beyond the seafloor; it could even reverberate through vast swaths of the oceanic food web, affecting not only marine life but perhaps our own. And while mining companies say these risks can be mitigated, some scientists question whether it’s even possible to fully predict the far-flung effects of seabed mining, and doubt whether it’s sensible to proceed if the consequences are so poorly understood.</description></item><item><title>The Robots Won’t Save Us Until We Control the Means of Production</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-robots-wont-save-us-until-we-control-the-means-of-production/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-robots-wont-save-us-until-we-control-the-means-of-production/</guid><description>The growing technological edge in finance capital does not mean that we should give up on fighting for the power of machines as tools for worker liberation. But the fact is, the owners own the machines. This is where Marx’s vision for automated liberation gets jammed up. It only works if the workers have control over the tools that are used to oppress them. Now, as in Marx’s time, they typically do not.</description></item><item><title>The Three-Body Problem</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-three-body-problem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-three-body-problem/</guid><description>“Now, faced with political cases like yours, all prosecutorial organs and courts would rather be too severe than too lax. This is because treating you too severely would just be a mistake in method, but treating you too laxly would be a mistake in political direction. (Location 513)
I was thinking about this for a while and I think it summarizes part of why a tough on crime approach cannot work for Dems and they instead need to adopt principles of [[restorative justice]] because once they adopt a &amp;ldquo;tough-on-crime&amp;rdquo; narrative, its hard to defend a line between what is necessary and unnecessary punishment, because any inclination towards mercy and justice will be lashed as letting criminals walk free.</description></item><item><title>The Tyranny of Convenience</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-tyranny-of-convenience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-tyranny-of-convenience/</guid><description>Convenience has the ability to make other options unthinkable. Once you have used a washing machine, laundering clothes by hand seems irrational, even if it might be cheaper. After you have experienced streaming television, waiting to see a show at a prescribed hour seems silly, even a little undignified. To resist convenience — not to own a cellphone, not to use Google — has come to require a special kind of dedication that is often taken for eccentricity, if not fanaticism.</description></item><item><title>The Web We Have to Save</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-web-we-have-to-save/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/the-web-we-have-to-save/</guid><description>People used to carefully read my posts and leave lots of relevant comments, and even many of those who strongly disagreed with me still came to read. Other blogs linked to mine to discuss what I was saying. I felt like a king. (View Highlight)
The hyperlink was my currency six years ago. Stemming from the idea of the hypertext, the hyperlink provided a diversity and decentralisation that the real world lacked.</description></item><item><title>This Drug Can Mend a Broken Heart</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/this-drug-can-mend-a-broken-heart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/this-drug-can-mend-a-broken-heart/</guid><description>“Memory reconsolidation” describes how, when we recall a memory, it can become pliable. There is hope—and some intriguing early data—that, at the moment of recollection, we might be able to intentionally change a memory and make it less burdensome. This ability to modulate distressing memories is being investigated as an intervention to treat post-traumatic stress disorder,1 addiction,2 phobias,3 and is thought to have promise for depression or anxiety more broadly. It rests on an idea that’s emerged from our understanding of memory over the past few decades: Memories are not fixed, even the ones that haunt us the most.</description></item><item><title>This Mesh We’re In - Why Communities Are Building an Internet That’s More Local</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/this-mesh-were-in-why-communities-are-building-an-internet-thats-more-local/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/this-mesh-were-in-why-communities-are-building-an-internet-thats-more-local/</guid><description>Subnodes, an open source project that turns the under-$50, credit-card-sized Raspberry Pi computer into a Wi-Fi router equipped with its own local web server and chat room. &amp;hellip; Subnodes could help artists set up local digital art galleries, or help activists or events organizers set up local, short-term message boards without having to work with big ISPs like Comcast or Time Warner Cable. “They could set up a network in a place that wouldn’t normally have connectivity, like a subway, or in a park, or really anywhere, because you’re the source of the network: you’re the server,” she says.</description></item><item><title>TLS</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/tls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/tls/</guid><description>Used to guarantee confidentiality, authenticity, and integrity in internet communications
Built on top of TCP
Protocol
Client sends nonce and list of encryption protocols it supports Server sends nonce, selected encryption protocol, and server&amp;rsquo;s public key signed by a certificate authority Generate Premaster Secret known only to client and server - can do this either with RSA or (EC-)DHE. DHE provides forward secrecy unlike RSA because if a private key is discovered later you can&amp;rsquo;t go back and decrypt older messages Attacks:</description></item><item><title>Tor</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/tor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/tor/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Tracking Identifiers</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/tracking-identifiers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/tracking-identifiers/</guid><description>Includes cookies, IP address, TLS state, browser fingerprint, phone number, MAC, advertising ID</description></item><item><title>Train Engineers Just Ousted Their Union President for Supporting the Rail Deal</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/train-engineers-just-ousted-their-union-president-for-supporting-the-rail-deal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/train-engineers-just-ousted-their-union-president-for-supporting-the-rail-deal/</guid><description>In an interview, Hall said his election spoke to rank-and-file frustrations that leadership failed to listen to the membership throughout the negotiations. “We have a union, but [members] are not involved,” he said. “I’m hoping to get out and listen to the membership.” (View Highlight)
Honestly sounds a lot like the frustrations with the UAW Strike where the bargaining team / union leadership seems very disconnected from the rank of file / actively tries to undermine them</description></item><item><title>Two Years Later, Where Is Occupy's Internet?</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/www.vice.com/en/article/kwpz8m/two-years-later-where-is-occupys-internet</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/www.vice.com/en/article/kwpz8m/two-years-later-where-is-occupys-internet</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about Occupy for a minute. How do you view the movement in hindsight? I said it from day one, and I will say it again: It was just a practice. We have a great deal of infrastructure to build before we can really start to talk about independence/autonomy/liberty/justice.
How might democratized tools and technologies play into popular unrest in the future? We will not rely upon tools that are designed to sell us out at our moment of greatest need.</description></item><item><title>UAW Strike</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/uaw-strike/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/uaw-strike/</guid><description>11/21
Joined a couple of the Signal GC&amp;rsquo;s relating to the strike and bargaining
UAW bargaining team caved on a cost of living adjustment in favor of 7% yearly raises to keep up with rising housing costs
So much disunity in all of the group chats
Disagreements around what terms like COLA mean
Disagreements about what the power of the strike comes from / when it&amp;rsquo;s highest
Personal call-outs and attacks along identity politics lines</description></item><item><title>Unions - Scale and Trust</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/unions-scale-and-trust/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/unions-scale-and-trust/</guid><description>As global supply chains have become more distributed since the mid-1990s due to international tariff and trade normalization, conglomerations of firms have been moving away from largely centralized enterprises – those that firm-oriented or trade-specific unions have traditionally been structured around – by shifting activities into component parts, distributed in such a way so as to gain comparative cost advantages in local material and labor markets. The new shape of production is therefore more of a diffuse, global network of firms, national regulatory contexts, and markets containing many and varied forms workers that fall through the cracks of union structures.</description></item><item><title>Unions Can Beat Anti-Labor Politicians</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/unions-can-beat-anti-labor-politicians/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/unions-can-beat-anti-labor-politicians/</guid><description>For the Ford administration, the demands of the education workers were not just about one subsector but a Trojan horse for gains across the public sector. They had to be aggressively contained.
This morphed a “normal” conflict with a set of employers (the school boards) into what was essentially a political strike against the government. The dilemma for the union was that in spite of the conflict’s significance for the entire public sector (and less directly, for private sector bargaining), the battle was being led and fought by only a subsector of the union movement.</description></item><item><title>url</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/url/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/url/</guid><description>Readwise</description></item><item><title>What Causes Alzheimer’s? Scientists Are Rethinking the Answer.</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/what-causes-alzheimers-scientists-are-rethinking-the-answer./</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/what-causes-alzheimers-scientists-are-rethinking-the-answer./</guid><description>science should encourage researchers to take different approaches. “But of course, in academic medicine and in commercial science, everybody has a lot riding on the outcome,” he said. “Careers are dependent upon the answer.” And there was a lot riding on the amyloid hypothesis. It takes on average more than a decade and $5.7 billion to develop a single drug for Alzheimer’s disease. “Pharmaceutical companies are not shy in saying that they’ve invested many billions of dollars in this,” Nixon said.</description></item><item><title>What Does Love Do to Us?</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/what-does-love-do-to-us/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/what-does-love-do-to-us/</guid><description>What happens when you fall in love for the first time is the activation of various areas of the limbic system and the neocortex. But we also see deactivations. These deactivations occur mainly in the brain area linked to “mentalizing.” Mentalizing is the ability to tell someone’s intentions, and you need to be good at mentalizing to spot a liar or a cheat. To be able to tell if somebody is lying, you need to be good at understanding what their motivation is.</description></item><item><title>What Is Populism?</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/what-is-populism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/what-is-populism/</guid><description>We simply do not have anything like a theory of populism, and we seem to lack coherent criteria for deciding when political actors turn populist in some meaningful sense.
it is a necessary but not sufficient condition to be critical of elites in order to count as a populist
populists are always antipluralist. Populists claim that they, and they alone, represent the people.
populism is always a form of identity politics (though not all versions of identity politics are populist)</description></item><item><title>When Breath Becomes Air</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/when-breath-becomes-air/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/when-breath-becomes-air/</guid><description>may be a one-time event, but living with terminal illness is a process.
Human knowledge is never contained in one person. It grows from the relationships we create between each other and the world, and still it is never complete.
You can’t ever reach perfection, but you can believe in an asymptote toward which you are ceaselessly striving.</description></item><item><title>whonix</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/whonix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/whonix/</guid><description> Anonymize against Tracking Identifiers
Protect against learning device address information from malicious JS/applets/Flash by
Making the IP address shared among all Whonix users or IP address of Tor exit relay Making the MAC address a virtual one different than the machine</description></item><item><title>Why a Messaging App Meant for Festivals Became Massively Popular During Hong Kong Protests</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/why-a-messaging-app-meant-for-festivals-became-massively-popular-during-hong-kong-protests/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/why-a-messaging-app-meant-for-festivals-became-massively-popular-during-hong-kong-protests/</guid><description>Unlike WhatsApp and other messaging apps, FireChat doesn’t require an internet connection for users to communicate. Instead, it uses a phone’s Bluetooth and Wi-Fi signals to connect it to other devices within a given range. In this setup, known as a mesh network , each phone acts as a node, and as more devices link together, the network’s range expands. Users can send texts and images under pseudonyms — another benefit for government-fearing protesters — though Open Garden recently introduced verified accounts for some journalists.</description></item><item><title>Wireless Local Networks_ WPA2</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/wireless-local-networks_-wpa2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/wireless-local-networks_-wpa2/</guid><description>Purpose: Communicate secures in a wireless local network
This is the protocol that&amp;rsquo;s used for wifi that has one password for every user
Has access point that&amp;rsquo;s constantly broadcasting beacon packets that contain the name of the network (akak the SSID - service set identifier)
PTK (Pairwise Transport Key) used to send messages from device to network and vice versa
GTK (Group Transport Key) used to broadcast messages to the entire network</description></item><item><title>Contents</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/contents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/contents/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Favorites</title><link>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/favorites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://githubuser.github.io/pages/favorites/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>